.danielle smalls



work experience

2018 Current Data and Deployment Strategist **Uncharted Software**

- · Performer on DARPA's Memex Program assisting initiative to scrape the Dark Web for illicit activities
- Facilitated training for law enforcement to use tools that aid in anti-human trafficking investigations
- Performed full-stack data analysis to understand user base including feature construction, visualization, etc.

Data Scientist | IST Research

2016-2018

- · Created new and modified existing tools to capture and analyze data gathered from hard to reach areas
- · Integrated analytical tools into social media data collection pipeline (Twitter, Facebook, Youtube)
- Built and implemented the analytical structure for ground-truth surveys regarding human trafficking, maternal health, military withdrawal, and other sociopolitical issues
- · Curated reports from active and passive monitoring architectures
- · Applied hidden population estimator to gage prevalence of human trafficking

Undergraduate Research Assistant 2013-2016 Virginia Tech

- · Re-designed survey tool to increase undergraduate response rates
- Facilitated data collection through interviews and "think-alouds"



stack experience

ElasticSearch tidyverse Shiny Hugo	Pandas Pytorch Keras Plotly	Numpy NLTK AWS Lambda gensim

☐ skills

R >>>>		
Python		
Machine Learning		
Statistics		



profile

Phone 571-723-8571 **Email** smalls.danielle@gmail.com **Address** Raleigh, North Carolina



• presentations

"Saying Yes: Reflections in the pursuit of a S.T.E.M career" | 2018

Keynote speaker for the 2018 cohort of C-Tech^2 hosted by Virginia Tech.

"Leading Ladies in STEM and Art" at George Washington University | 2018

Panelist for SUPERGirls Shine Foundation discussing female engagement and empowerment in STEM fields.

"Does Motivation Matter for Conceptual Change: **Developing Effective Qualitative Research** Approaches." | 2015

ASEE Annual Conference and Exposition.

"Do You Want to Take a Survey? Exploring Tools to Increase Undergraduate Student Response Rates to

Real-Time Experience Surveys." | 2013 & 2014 Danielle Smalls, Dr. Holly Matusovich, Dr. Rachel Mccord

ASEE Annual Conference and Exposition (2014) Conference on Higher Education Pedagogy (2013)



education

B.S. Statistics 2010-2016 Virginia Polytechnic Institute & State University

Current Related Coursework: Udacity Pytorch Scholarship winner. In pursuit of deep learning nanodegree.